Come together.
Deadpool & Wolverine is a action, comedy, science
fiction film directed by Shawn Levy.
A listless Wade Wilson toils away in civilian life with his days as
the morally flexible mercenary, Deadpool, behind him.
But when his homeworld faces an existential threat, Wade must
reluctantly suit-up again with an even more reluctant Wolverine.
Wade Wilson / Deadpool / Nicepool, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Logan / Wolverine, played by Hugh Jackman.
Cassandra Nova, played by Emma Corrin.
Mr. Paradox, played by Matthew Macfadyen.
Laura / X-23, played by Dafne Keen.
Happy Hogan, played by Jon Favreau.
Deadpool & Wolverine is a 2024 American superhero film based on Marvel
Comics featuring the characters Deadpool and Wolverine.
Produced by Marvel Studios, Maximum Effort, and 21 Laps Entertainment, and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it
is the 34th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU) and the sequel to Deadpool (2016) and Deadpool 2 (2018).
The film was directed by Shawn Levy from a screenplay he wrote with
Ryan Reynolds, Rhett Reese, Paul Wernick, and Zeb Wells.
Reynolds and Hugh Jackman respectively star as Wade Wilson / Deadpool and Logan / Wolverine, alongside Emma
Corrin, Morena Baccarin, Rob Delaney, Leslie Uggams, Aaron Stanford, and Matthew Macfadyen.
In the film, Deadpool works with a reluctant Wolverine from another universe to stop
the Time Variance Authority (TVA) from destroying his own universe.
Development on a third Deadpool film began at 20th Century Fox by November 2016, but was
moved to Marvel Studios when Fox was acquired by Disney in March 2019.
Wendy Molyneux and Lizzie Molyneux-Logelin joined in November 2020 as writers.
Levy was hired to direct in March 2022, when Reese and Wernick
returned from the previous films for rewrites.
The creative team had difficulty settling on a story until Jackman decided to reprise
his role as Wolverine from Fox's X-Men film series in August 2022.
Several other actors from the X-Men films and other Marvel productions also returned as
part of a multiverse story, which serves as a tribute to Fox's Marvel films.
Filming began in May 2023, taking place at Pinewood Studios, Bovingdon
Studios, and Norfolk in England as well as Los Angeles.
Production was suspended in July due to the 2023 SAG-AFTRA strike.
Filming resumed in November and wrapped in January 2024.
The title was revealed a month later.
The film's soundtrack features an original score by Rob Simonsen and numerous
existing songs, including Madonna's "Like a Prayer" for key sequences.
Deadpool & Wolverine is the first R-rated MCU film, retaining
that rating from the prior Deadpool films.
Deadpool & Wolverine premiered on July 22, 2024, at the David H.
Koch Theater in New York City, and was released in the United
States on July 26 as part of Phase Five of the MCU.
Critics praised the performances of Reynolds and Jackman as well as the
humor, but were less positive about the film overall.
It was a commercial success, grossing $1.338 billion worldwide and becoming the second-highest-grossing film of 2024, the
highest-grossing R-rated film ever, and the 20th-highest-grossing film ever at the time of its release.
With a net production budget of $429 million, Deadpool & Wolverine is
believed to be one of the most expensive films ever made.
It received various accolades.
The film explores themes of hero, superhero, anti
hero, mutant, breaking the fourth wall.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.